<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="./FlowConfig.rng"?>
<FlowConfig>
  <page title="Deductions" route="deductions.html">
    <section>
      <h2>Standard or Itemized Deductions</h2>
      <p>Standard or itemized deductions reduce the amount of tax you owe.</p>
      <p>Most people take the standard deduction, but you can itemize your deductions if you have a mortgage, large gifts to charity, or large medical expenses. For most people, the standard deduction amount is higher than the amount they'd get by itemizing.</p>
      <p/>
      <fg-set path="/wantsItemizedDeduction">
        <question>
          Do you want to check what your itemized deduction would be?
        </question>
        <input type="boolean"/>
      </fg-set>
      <h2 condition="/wantsItemizedDeduction" operator="isTrue">Itemized Deductions</h2>
      <h2>Qualified mortgage interest and investment interest expenses</h2>
      <p>If you borrowed money to buy a home or investment property, you can deduct the interest you paid on that loan. You can also deduct your mortgage insurance premiums.</p>
      <p>Learn more about mortgage interest and investment interest [X].</p>
      <fg-set path="/qualifiedMortgageInterestAndInvestmentInterestExpenses">
        <question>Qualified interest</question>
        <input type="dollar"/>
      </fg-set>
      <h2>State and Local Taxes</h2>
      <p>There are four types of State and Local Taxes: 1) State, local, and foreign income taxes;
      2) State and local general sales taxes; 3) State and local real estate taxes; 4) State and
        local personal property taxes</p>
      <p>There is a $40,000 deduction cap on SALT payments</p>
      <fg-set path="/stateAndLocalTaxPayments/">
        <question>Total state or local tax payments by recipient</question>
        <input type="dollar"/>
      </fg-set>
      <h2>Medical and dental expenses deduction</h2>
      <p>Total expenses that exceed 7.5% of your Estimated medical and dental expenses Can include
      the total estimated amount paid for health insurance premiums, not including any amount the
        employer pays</p>
      <fg-set path="/medicalAndDentalExpenses/">
        <question>Total amount for a single medical or dental expense category</question>
        <input type="dollar"/>
      </fg-set>
      <h2>Gifts to charity</h2>
      <fg-set path="/charitableContributions/">
        <question>Total contribution amount from a specific charitable contribution</question>
        <input type="dollar"/>
      </fg-set>
      <h2>Casualty losses</h2>
      <p>Casualty and theft losses relating to your home, household items, and vehicles if
        the loss took place in a federally declared disaster area</p>
      <fg-set path="/casualtyLossesTotal">
        <question>Total casualty loss from a specific loss event</question>
        <input type="dollar"/>
      </fg-set>
      <h2>Other itemized deductions</h2>
      <p>You can deduct any of these expenses...</p>
      <fg-set path="/otherDeductionsTotal/">
        <question>Other deductions</question>
        <input type="dollar"/>
      </fg-set>
    </section>
  </page>
</FlowConfig>
